[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
[Music]
s
learn to have better conversations with
ourselves
[Music]
knowledge is power
reality is
[Music]
broadcast still like for the instruments
and their reverbs and stuff it's
underrated uh so I it is I I mean I
played with it a little bit
um
on my phone and whatnot but I need more
capabilities like so I actually started
out
um before like the beat making and all
that like engineering
like sessions and mixing and mastering
so it was more like
vocal processing
um
and you know also producing in a way to
to the point to where I do produce now
as well and then um I got into some of
the video stuff as well
well let's let's break it down let's
start from the beginning so people who
don't know you don't know what you do
they haven't heard of you yet assume um
give them like a little bio and then
let's start back like when you started
uh working with audio and learning about
engineering and stuff let's let's start
with that after you give a little bio
yeah man uh anyways uh thank you shout
out to you for having me on bro for real
uh it's been a minute honestly I'm
surprised I haven't been on one before
um I would say man the podcast realm is
crazy but you know what
consistency is everything bro
and you've been doing this media [__]
this type of [__] forever bro and you
gotta leg up on some cats you want to
Spring Forward you're gonna spring
forward bro this [__] gonna happen I
appreciate you for saying it but it's
Bobby bars two r's one Z don't get it
twisted you know uh two R stands for the
realest and the rarest and if you stay
real you're gonna stay rare cause they
don't make them like us no more you feel
me
they really don't they really don't
um you know I'm CEO and creator of big
bad Studios
uh my dog is a logo he'd be singing on
the mic you know uh Ace Boogie might
bring him up here for a little bit but
you know I make music
I got a studio on Studio we called the
big bet also it's a brand an
entertainment company big bet creative
house we're just trying to be creative
run everything up in every direction
um I got about 20 songs in my catalog
out on all platforms and released
and about five times that in the vault
uh you know it's all about creativity
running it up
um I had to stay in the workforce and
I'm still in the workforce in order to
put myself in the position to follow my
dreams and you know
sometimes it's just about putting
yourself in the position to
figure out what you want to do or what
you're supposed to be doing you know
like it doesn't happen at the same time
for everybody you know but we all got
responsibilities to ourselves and
past Day loyal to our dreams I like that
you're real about that too by the way I
like that you're like not trying to
front you're like yeah I'm working too
you know like
I feel like that's dope in a in a world
of Hip-Hop Hip-Hop you know very well
it's just front and left and right so
it's dope to just be real
hey man I grew like I ain't gonna lie I
grew up doing a lot of things that
people in the hip-hop culture I guess
we're portraying
um you know I I did my dirt and hustled
in the streets
uh was blessed to stay on the outs and
have enough sense to get out when it was
time while I was ahead
and uh
just realized that
I have to earn my dreams and in order to
do that it just means putting myself in
the position to
even set goals for that
you know it's like you can set goals but
I want to set
obtainable goals which
I guess in a bigger picture gives me
makes me like
set a goal to myself to where I'm like
yeah I'm gonna go ahead and just do what
I gotta do to get there but
having patience knowing that's gonna
come
and just doing you and you know what I
came I started rapping when I was 29 G
oh yeah
what 32
well I'll be 32 in April so I'm 31 right
now
um
but I've been rapping my whole life I
started making music officially like
that but I think it was at a good time
because man if I would have been making
music back in the day when I had no
sense
it would have been ratchet and it would
you know you was DJing and I'm sure you
DJ'd a lot of Ratchet [__] and I
probably would have been the Cobra to
some of it and and not to say it would
have been a terrible thing or a good
thing just that now it's just it's just
me and who I am and I've been through
some things I'm damn near just spitting
game on every track
um the Artistry is different though man
like I don't know if you heard too much
of my music I dabbled through I didn't I
didn't listen deeply so so explore I
dabbled through it though
yeah I recommend a couple tracks for you
um I'm a spiritual man you know
um some of it's on some
spiritual stuff you know like I got a
song called God got me that just a
couple months ago turned a year old
um was actually my first like real on my
second first real official music video
um was the first like real big back
collab out of big bad Studios uh my
in-house producer JC Banco shout out to
him
um we got a lot of music coming out as
well but
that was our first track together
um
I got man my very first music video was
that feel blessed song you know and I
ain't gonna lie I went from having like
some younger fans on some like
whatever [__] onto having like some 80
year old fans like yeah nephew you know
like
that's dope though that's kind of tight
like you don't even really expect that
no but the demographic don't matter
because I ain't gonna lie I don't Target
these young kids with what I say bro
because inevitably everyone gonna grow
up and get some sense you know and like
I'm thinking of myself in the future I
don't have children yet I did just get
married uh last year congratulations uh
we're going on we're going on eight
months thank you and um
but when I'm when I'm a dad you know I
want to put my kids up on some
definite things that have to do with my
culture you know but on some music
that's going to inspire them
to do the right thing versus
you know these ignorant things that
these kids are even lying about
on wraps you know like things that they
think that they should be doing and it's
just like you know so with that being
said I'm also just keeping it real and
telling my story and whether you fan on
my story or not that's cool but I got 20
tracks on all platforms available for
everybody uh for free streaming and
purchasing
um I guarantee everybody to find a
handful
put on a playlist you know everything
ain't for everybody but my first my
first uh piece of work as far as other
than a single like my first EP was
called they ain't ready and I had like a
song for all them like I had a cookout
song a dance song uh a chill back song
uh heartbreak song You Know seven tracks
all just different things just to show
my versatility nice just like you you
you're gonna find something for you in
there I love that all right so where did
this come from you said you've been kind
of like writing and [__] your whole life
but you didn't start really putting
tracks down until you're 29. like what
what started because even like we can go
back to like when we knew each other you
know like I didn't know you as an artist
I would say so I didn't know that so I
was always a free styling oh yeah right
okay yeah live bro you kicked out if you
kicked it with me in a certain way I'd
be you would know and they would tell
you I'm that dude that said hey man turn
on the beat love it
like let's get it um
I definitely always freestyle honestly
I started writing like maybe a year
before I started doing music officially
um but still to this day a lot of my
best friends come from freestyles
so I just I don't know Innovative myself
and like I told like every time I
freestyle would be crazy
and because I didn't really
have much time with the pending pad I
mainly had time on a beat just coming
off the top and then I ended up just
like voice memo on my phone you know
and I would just record that then I'll
take some of those lyrics and just
refine it and proofread it you know and
then I learned how
how I rap and then how to write to that
so you got to a point where you're like
I actually have some [__] to say like
let's let's record this like because
what because I mean you're talking about
like you're writing more spiritual stuff
now I bet you if you're anything like me
man a few years ago spiritual [__] would
have went right over my head man I'm
into it now like I understand it now and
like I've had like a whole revamp of
understanding myself and in God and like
just just all this [__] you know but
like and you know you know how many
other people going through the same
thing though yeah that's what I'm trying
to tell you like Great Awakening stay
consistent and stay real
my fault to cut you off but that's
because bro that that's how it is you
know yeah yeah like you grow everyone
grows inevitably at least you know grow
up yeah get older and realize I need I
need something and and when I say
spiritual you know it's more like just
man stands to who you are
and and and in order to do that you got
to find out who you are you know but
sometimes you gotta dig deep it's
different for everybody but that's why I
say I do musics music through all the
emotions I've been through
you feel me so I go back to stories from
back then like how I felt what I went
through all the way to present day
yeah no you have like a little
perspective on them you can see him from
a distance with a little bit of
knowledge on them a little bit of like
grown man perspective on the thing
exactly yeah
but yeah what were you saying like a few
years ago you said that would have went
over your head yeah yeah no no I was
just saying like because me like the way
I write and everything now too is like
inevitably I mean other people
the word spiritual or like God or like
any of that stuff I know it's so loaded
like if you don't know like like when I
say that word it has such a heavy
meaning to everybody who hears it you
know and I get that and it's a totally
different word for everybody that has
their own individual characteristics but
I do think that there's definitely and
especially just as like an artist and a
Creator and like someone who has always
kind of like lived out loud there's for
sure like a before and after of like my
Evolution as a person like who who I am
as a man and just as like a human being
there's for sure like a before and after
of like the spiritual understanding of
the self of philosophy of like
understanding like what happened to me
when I was a kid and how it made me who
I am today and like how I can reject
these things and like build up on these
things and develop my character and find
my own values and all that sort of [__]
like it was just like a few years ago I
started like really stumbling into that
and so the reason why I ask and the
reason why I like explain mine is
because like I think it's pretty
profound bro like it's some might say
it's just grown going up it's just kind
of like being an adult you kind of just
get to a point you got to get your [__]
together in a sense sure but I don't
know man I think it's pretty profound I
think a lot of people go through it and
they feel like they're kind of [__]
losing it in the middle of it and if
they just knew that like oh actually if
I just buckle down learn about myself
read some read some books listen to some
YouTube lectures like I'm gonna come out
on the other side you know with with my
Artistry intact so to say
I think regardless it has to do with
kind of like what you said going back in
going back in your head through what you
went through and learned from it like
even if you didn't learn from it in that
moment
like realize oh [__] well if I would
have done this or you know carried
myself in that way or whatever
you know or you know with that being
said I'm not living life with no regrets
but I'm still like in my head watching
game film
you know watching game film on like
all right well if I didn't do it right
that time let's make sure I do it right
the next time
because any time that you spent that you
didn't learn something is a bad
investment a bad investment
you know like if you gonna invest
anytime into anything you better learn
something if anything
right there you know because bro like
I've been through trials and
tribulations I've been through
situations that you could call unfair
I've been through situations you call
unfortunate and fortunate but I know how
to count my blessings you know what I
mean
um and with that being said
I've
God God blessed me with the strength to
know when to quit
and when I say quit I mean Veer from
negative things in my life that brought
positive things like money and whatever
can you explain them what do you mean by
like fear from negative things like just
trying to think like somebody else is
kind of going through it right now what
what might they correlate with
uh you know God's Gonna guide you down
the right path sometimes there might be
a fork in the road you know
um I guess to make long story short the
harder right over the easier wrong
um yeah me like
it's easy to just give up on your goals
it's easy to just succumb to things
but it's hard to push through it's hard
to climb Hills it's hard to jump over
hurdles
but
except that
if you don't have the strength to jump
over them hurdles at this point in time
that
you gonna do whatever it takes to get
the strength let me jump over it the
next time
because inevitably it's gonna happen
again because you're gonna live life
right
and it's just accepting that life is
gonna throw you some things and either
you wait on that curveball or
you swing too early
and when you swing too early it's easy
to just swing early instead of just
waiting on it because you scared of
missing that ball
you know and there's like three
analogies in one I know that was all
over the place but yeah yeah people are
following that's that's how it works
that's how podcast conversations work
you just share what you're going through
and it's sometimes it's working for
somebody else that ain't exactly you
when you're talking so yeah but I mean
that's kind of why I when you said that
I felt that way
explaining a couple more ways but yeah
man I
I just feel like you just you gotta
count your blessings man
um
and there's always a path man
there's always a path for you you know
um go ahead bro did you so like I mean a
few minutes ago you mentioned like okay
you just got married too and you
mentioned you're talking about like your
future son
I think that's I think that's really
dope because I think a lot of people a
lot of people listen and might not even
think in that in that perspective like
my future son I mean that's like kind of
the perspective change that could change
your life that could change every like
action that you do if you're thinking
how can this benefit my future child
like do you know what like have you
always thought that way is that more
recent is that more coming with like
just just growing up and learning about
yourself and stuff
yeah I mean I know what I aspire to be
yeah
you know what I mean I aspire to be a
good father
and I aspire to be one in the first
place but
um
to be a good father I aspired to
bring in uh you know upstanding young
man or young woman into this world
and make sure that they know what they
need to know
um
so they don't make the mistakes I made
right so that way they got one leg up
they're gonna make their own mistakes
and we all know that you know but I
didn't make all the mistakes my pops
made he told me a lot of the [__] he did
and he kept it real with me
um
I think I definitely will approach you
know raising my kids differently but as
far as like the way I approach
everything in life is no regrets bro you
know
um not ignorantly going in like
Worldstar but it's like you know I mean
it's like I'm gonna do what I need to do
and also what the [__] I wanna do yeah
like I deserve it and I've earned it
yeah and there's nobody who can tell me
otherwise like I'm doing
were I need to be doing yeah and so with
this music stuff
the goal is obviously to have it
be a future but man it's just it's an
outlet and you know the way the music
business is now is it's a whole business
you know like
um doing music at the capacity of our
life too
um
isn't something that's just a pastime
yeah it is another job you're taking on
yeah for sure but it's more than just
the music because like I got the merch
for sale
um I do the comedy stuff I got a little
slogan like what you're not gonna do you
know
um I got the gear the show Money
starting to come you know the merch
money starting to come he was starting
to book me future money starting to come
and I'm almost five years in man I'm
gonna lie my wife told me this story
about this uh
it's like a Japanese like bamboo tree or
whatever that they plant in the ground
and it takes five years for it to even
break the soil
but you still have to nurture it
underground hoping that five years is
gonna grow even though you can't see
nothing you're supposed to just have
faith on you can't keep digging it up
make sure it's growing bro but after
that five years like it grows
and a copious amount of feet per year
exponentially yeah
bro just
and that's why I'm trying to say like
that's kind of like a weird metaphor for
like what I'm doing most people ain't
got the courage or the drive or the
faith in themselves to take a journey
like that for five years without knowing
what's going to come out of it
and it's like
man they say don't put all your eggs in
one basket but
we think the eggs came from
hmm
you know some more eggs G yeah yeah you
just have some more eggs Gene get
another basket yeah yeah yeah yeah
you know yeah you got to go all in bro I
mean why not too I like you can go all
in more than once though and it's all
about doing it in the right way well and
it's not like it's I mean like we think
of the word failure is almost like it
don't really exist I feel like in our
circles I mean to outside people they
think it does but it really ain't really
a word to us because it's like like what
what do you like if you're not at the
top of the Spotify playlist at the end
of five years it's like what you didn't
just take five years of straight up
learning every day like you're learning
about building a business you're
learning about thumbnails you're
learning how YouTube Works you're
learning how this amp works you like
you're learning so much every everything
that I know bro is for me just trying
[__] when I was like 16. it's nuts yeah
bro I literally bro I literally I mean
like I don't know if you ever went but
like I I literally started this whole
thing throwing random illegal parties in
the woods bro like that's how I knew how
to I've been to a couple yeah like
that's that's I started doing that stuff
nobody taught me anything it's just like
you got to keep trying it's like maybe I
didn't hit the goals that I wanted to
hit or maybe I was aiming for different
[__] but like look at all this stuff I
know now I learned all this stuff I'm
just trying bro just throw it out the
wall believe in yourself for half a day
and just do it bro just do it yeah and
then I saw you I saw you DJing at the at
the clubs and the bars I've been to like
two weddings you DJ that like come on
man
yeah I mean crazy stuff like that and
it's and the thing is bro with me it's
like it's not even like if you ask me at
any point in those like hey do you want
to like you want to be a famous DJ like
what are you trying to do are you trying
to make at me I'm just like I just love
DJing I just love doing this I'm just
trying to take it day by day like you
know there's a lot of ways where I think
having your sights on a goal is helpful
and there's a lot of ways where I'm like
maybe I could have had more
opportunities if I was a little more
clear on my vision there is aspects of
that but I don't know man sometimes I
look back I'm like you know I made it
pretty far I'm doing all right by just
working you know just doing my thing
yeah do you still DJ yeah yeah
definitely I uh I'm not playing as much
I'm not like in clubs and bars and stuff
I just don't have like a ton of urge to
do it I just want to be in bed by 9 30.
taking gigs yeah but I'm doing like
corporate stuff random gigs I fly out
like a couple months ago I flew out to
uh LA to DJ like some cage fights like
random stuff like that I'll get booked
for so it it's dope I still I still get
to do like some really cool DJ stuff but
I'm not you know out in clubs every
weekend or nothing
but nice that's what's up at least you
still get to like get your fixed yeah
yeah you know when it's you know I've
been I feel like I spent a lot more of
my time even just at home when I'm
creating I'm writing my own stuff I I
love to like just write hip-hop and
poetry and it's cool to try to combine
I've done a few shows now here in Austin
where I'm like DJing but I'm also
rapping and like that's potentially
cringy you know like that's potentially
no [__] way but but uh I've been I'm
rapping oh yeah dude I've been spinning
a lot that's that's why I've been
spending a lot of my time doing is
writing and rapping bro is it you didn't
send me anything then is it out uh I
don't have anything on Spotify I'll send
you some stuff that you have to check
out you got like some clips some ciphers
or something yeah yeah yeah I got some
clips and then I've got some [__] um
I've got some like fully recorded stuff
that I haven't mastered or anything but
it's I just haven't put it on Spotify
I'm trying to be hey are you gonna try
to release some music
yeah I think so I uh I'm being a
perfectionist about Spotify but you know
um
hey man
um holler at me I think there's a couple
things I can help you with just because
for the last like four or five years
this is all I've been researching and
doing
um but well [__] let's have a
conversation now bro yeah and there's
plenty of things you probably helped me
out with too but man I want to actually
clap with you too you know uh there's
another dude I went to school with that
went to school in uh I think well
obviously you know Roman Merrell I know
Roman yeah bro I just I just had him on
the podcast oh you did yeah yeah okay
yeah he do music too man and it's kind
of crazy man a lot of folks I know from
back in the day be doing stuff like that
it's like man why are we all like get
together and do something you know what
it's all love though when we do connect
though we're all like this like the same
with me and Roman we're like bro let's
let's connect so yeah bro like anytime
you got anything send it back and forth
then let's link up let's let's have a
combo about that I would love to like
write together get on some stuff like I
mean you said you're mixing in your
engineering and stuff too I mean I'm I'm
doing I'm not the greatest G yeah you
got Beats
yeah actually I got a few so I mainly I
mainly stuck like I got tired of waiting
on folks who'd be packed and I probably
should have been a producer first hang a
lot because I'm pretty cool with it but
I already started pursuing the rapping
and songwriting [__] where so I was just
kind of bringing that to fruition and
then starting to dabble on the beach
and bro as an artist thing it's been
starting to work like I see my hard
labor paying off like this show I did on
Saturday bro probably one of my best
sets I threw a couple jokes in between
love it
and that open mic stuff's been helping
it's helping too and then bro I sold I
sold like 150 in merch
damn that's what's up in person that
night you know and I got
I got like what was it 40 of the door
nice that's good whatever that was you
know it was a decent turnout too yeah I
mean dude that's hard sometimes even
being promoter like especially in a in
in a rap environment it's sometimes hard
to ask for any amount of the door
sometimes it's just like hey we're just
grateful to be playing we'll do what you
say so it's nice that you're able to get
some of the door too
yeah I mean I think just because the way
the way I've been doing things it I
think they kind of just expect it now
yeah like because not to say I'm like
trying to gorilla pimp the game I've
been putting people on and trying to
give a lot of people opportunities you
can't really put anyone on you can just
give them opportunities it's whatever
they do with it you know but I'll be
I'll be helping folks out and um man
with the studio it's huge like so I live
with my wife at this house but just like
three blocks down is the house that I
bought when I was 25. I rented out to my
producer and then I still have the
studio that I have access to excellent
so I rent him the whole house other than
that bedroom and then a part of the
garage where I got some storage but
and we actually turned the garage into
the podcast and um the voice acting area
yeah nice dude this is what we're doing
all that yeah that's how you got the
podcast going too it looked dope I
listened to it for a little bit I mean
you were saying the editing is what
takes a while to to get it out you know
that's the same thing over here bro man
that was super early
um
but yes just
the guy who we had editing it we had
like something real going everyone had
to start working like out I've been
essential G I never got none of that
time off everyone else did
um but my peers they all did
our producer did and then so did uh the
my drone guy swing
to check him out he's got pretty pop in
YouTube
um
he's actually getting his uh part 107
license so you can do this commercially
but
um I got a music video coming out that's
like 90 Drone footage oh I love that
drone dude drone just drilling shots are
so nice unreal
it's crazy he's so good at it dude's got
like 30 different drones and like builds
them and stuff and [__]
um but he was doing all the editing I
hooked him up with the software and all
that
um so he does the music videos and stuff
now but he had to work full time
um obviously the supplement his income
until he gets his part 107 he start
flying commercially yeah of course but
you guys are making time to like still
create and when you can you're doing
what you can I mean I like any sort of
collaboration any sort of like Community
Building I'm always like hell yeah oh
yeah yeah so we're actually trying to
build a team um it's just myself him and
then my producer JC
and then my dog aches because he's a
mascot but uh that's that's the big bad
team other than you know everyone else
who
of support we got uh patreon and all
that stuff too nice um
I need to start posting on there on
there more but it's big best Studios on
there it's part of it it's part of it
posting man it's like keep keeping up
with all the social medias you know you
heard the chat GPT this new AI the new
algorithm you heard of this
there's going to be basically I bring it
up within this next year I feel like
we're going to have some help as
creators and people there's going to be
more options for us to like basically
make a make you know YouTube video right
the description write the title hit
click and it's going to populate to all
these sites and like make it the right
size and all that sort of [__] for us I
think that's coming this year to make it
super easy for us creators so we're on
all the platforms but we're just you
know we're only taking an hour instead
of all day just to post all these
platforms
technology is coming
yeah but
it'll just get more complicated
as there's you know I mean like
as the size has changed and the [__]
changed and I was gonna come out with
AI to help you do that but then it's
going to upgrade and then we're gonna
have to change it to you know what I
mean then you got to learn how to use
the AI properly it's never ending it's
never ending like that bro I'm I'm
pretty old school bro
uh I wouldn't have no social media if I
didn't have to as an artist uh
man I come from being an athlete and
like my pops raised me to be kind of
militant man what we got in trouble he
missed push-ups and sit-ups and all that
stuff
and say yes ma'am yes sir you know and I
come from a little bit different
background but I think just enough where
I was raised and where I lived you
probably wouldn't guess that you know
and I got a song coming up January 4th
called Hold It Down
and it's kind of like
a black history history month type song
but like it's my story on
you know social inequality and and the
struggles of being mixed race kind of
you know like people tell me I'm too
white to be black or too black to be
white but who the [__] is they to tell
me
who I am you're trying to make you feel
like you don't fit in somewhere yeah but
but with that being said I think just
the way I handle it not saying everyone
does that way because it can be tough
for a lot of people I understand but
I just it made me in tune with myself
it's like who are they tell me who I am
or who I'm not I know who I am you know
what I embrace and I've been me my whole
life I never changed for no check
I ain't never changed for no fat I ain't
it never changed for no click
this is me and who I'll always be
but who I am today ain't who I will
become because I'm gonna do nothing but
get better not what I do you know
therefore no one will ever be able to do
what I do
because only I do this
and I I advise everyone else to do the
same be the best they can be at what
they do I mean you can't even put a
title on what it is I do because
only I have the capability to do it
constant have you always had a growth
mindset is this like did your parents
help you build this when you were young
like have you always because there's
like a fish mindset versus a growth
mindset I feel like
uh
I mean I think a lot of it came from
like playing sports and [__]
you know but my parents didn't
necessarily grind that into me
um but it's more like always wanting to
be better
like
I don't know like I said I'm a spiritual
man as well I treat others as I like to
be treated you know I believe in being
kind and you know good karma and stuff
um
is is it's about growth though too like
I want to be the best I can be
I just I think I just been in top with
reality I know that I can only control
what the [__] I can control gee it's not
like
things are against me I think it is like
[__] I'm supposed to go through this
because you know if I continue to get
weaker then life just gonna beat me the
hell down but bro that's why I pointed
out because like what you got something
that's like really wise like you like
this your ability to do that and be like
like no I'm not taking no for an answer
like no I'm not that I'm gonna grow more
every day like who you knew yesterday
you know today like that like it takes
people years to even like awaken that or
even discover that within themselves so
it's like I feel like you even just
sharing your story especially through
music too you know like you probably
have the same thing when we grew up when
we're listening to artists share their
story kind of the same thing it inspires
us and helps us kind of like see that
vision of our own life being a growth
mindset you know from other people
sharing their stories so it's
for real I would say there's not like a
whole lot of shock value in keeping it
real like that when you don't live in
like you know a hood where there's crazy
[__] going on like we heard growing up
but with that being said man
I think if you really listen like
I've been real I keep I keep it real and
I do nothing but tell my story like my
pops told me he goes man
he goes what you do is so complicated
but so goddamn simple at the same time
you ain't doing nothing but tell them
what you did or what you went through
you know exactly exactly awesome [__]
like I'm just like yeah he's like bro
he's like son you just telling your
story
and I said exactly because if you live
in life you ain't never gonna run out of
content gee as long as you keep it real
and never gonna run out of content
because every day is something different
and you know they say it's what you make
it life is what you make it but
it's honestly where you perceive it to
be if you perceive things to be terribly
bad then a but
you also gotta like
not just be
perceiving life as what it is in that
moment
until you can have that mindset to step
back because you know how people they
get older and they're able to step back
from situations from the past and then
look at it and learn from it but if you
can do that in real time
growth is crazy bro don't wait don't
wait
natural growth man yeah yeah yeah that
self-awareness bro a lot of people like
that self-awareness is a profound thing
to like really notice man like wait hold
up my action I'm responsible for this
like my actions are why I'm where I'm at
like
the the things that I think about are
what create my future you know that's
and that's heavy because that's a big
responsibility to take on and truly
accept but I feel like it's such a
freeing thing at the same time to really
know like man my mind is my
responsibility
yeah facts I think people just trying to
always tell me
like
who I was or who I wasn't
just like made me make some value to
myself that like
I was always going to stay true to
myself whether other people thought I
was or was not
like I'm not gonna let someone to say oh
you're white so I'm gonna start acting
white or say oh you're too black tell me
I'm gonna start acting black I'm gonna
be me whatever I am is me yeah I mean I
don't need to fall under no stereotype
but with that being said I had to stay
tapped into who I really was it's like
oh am I what they say I am or am I not
what they say I am with the whoop you
know to the point to where it wasn't
even a question it couldn't be it's like
that's to the point to where it's like
okay say what you want to say but
now now being consistent all 31 and a
half years of my life you know it's like
hey yo that [__] here you go his music
do that you know I'm still who I was and
who y'all said I wasn't but who I've
been you know like
I don't necessarily need to prove nobody
right because only person I need to
prove it to myself is myself
and as long as I know that what I'm
doing is what I need to be doing then
I'm good bro
honestly if I if I tell myself something
like I got Pride just like if and I if I
tell you I'm gonna do something I'm
gonna do it right my word is bond also
to myself
but if I tell myself hey you gonna do
this
I gotta do it and there's a type of
Pride and a sense of urgency and you
know to where I gotta make sure I get
this [__] done because I hold a
professional relationship with myself as
well you know
bro that's huge that builds too like
keeping promises to yourself doing what
you say you're gonna do like don't
wiggle out of your own [__] because
we're always going to find ways if we
want to seek that Comfort we'll always
find ways to wiggle out of our own [__]
man I still do it all the time man and
I'm like damn I know I know better you
know like when I when I catch myself
like not mate not meeting commitments
that I made for myself or like not
showing up on time when I said I was
going to show up on time you got to
notice that [__] because like those
little habits you're right man they
build up they're gonna make you who you
are
for real yeah yeah everybody knows it
but not everyone accepts what it is
I mean if you don't accept it you're
kind of denying you're kind of like
lying to life in a sense like life is
gonna
well unfortunately a lot of folks do
that
well but bro it's like what's crazy
is like even if you want to deny it
there is that little voice in your head
telling you like when you're doing the
wrong thing that voice never goes away
bro it's still kind of like I don't like
it like all right you can do it but like
you know it ain't right you know it's
still kind of there like and you just
all right you still acting you know the
trick is man listen that voice because
you know damn well that's right you know
yeah yeah hey bro everybody got that go
ahead yeah yeah they do it's our
conscious man it's our higher self it's
our it's what makes us we're always
capable of being better than we are
right now and it's worth feeding you
know and we all get the voice
um hey I want to ask you about like your
writing process like I always love I
think that's always super fascinating I
think people who are artists can hear
other people's writing process and like
go oh I want to try that and then I also
think people who don't write they don't
know anything about music except for
like yo it like it hits hard and I think
it's dope like I love to listen to it my
car I don't know anything about it I
think they even think that it's really
dope to hear like how does someone even
think of this stuff to write how do they
get like their words or something like
you went through how do you make that
rhyme and like put it in a track like do
you Do You Freestyle a lot of the stuff
do you write do you sit down with a pen
and Pad like what's your process been
like
I mean
man it definitely varies and I've owned
it in
um I do got a little bit of a formula
but
when I just get Beats right so I get a
beat pack
I'll listen to the beats and whatever
the Beats make me feel like right so
like I'll jump into that mode and if
there's like
story that I could think of or an
emotion or
some type of event that happened
say it's a party song think of a night
we was at the club you know so you know
and I'll think of it and try to go
through a scenario and make it make
sense
um
also you know
I think of rhymes
not always when I'm listening to beats
though you know so that freestyle part
of me and then like I said the whole
progression of recording myself on the
phone was freestyling and then getting
bro my pen is on fire now like it's Penn
Griffey it's out of here
yeah bro and
I'm doing nothing but getting better but
it's it's just crazy I've expedited a
lot of time with the work I've put in
you know and um
so I'll take an emotion you know maybe I
didn't fully get over it maybe I was
just going through it or maybe
it's something I never really spoke
about you know and
um I'll take and I'll take that emotion
I'll let out on the track
you know like there's one coming out
like I got a verse that said like you
know they try to tell me who I am
instead of trying to find out about a
Mean Mug no Slayer people's eyebrow
you know and then the rest of it talks
about the inequality stuff and y'all
listen to us come out February 4th call
hold it down
um you know the very last verse starts
out they try to tell me I was to uh
to why to be black and too black to be
white you know and then I'll run it up
with that and it's just about
what I went through and what I never
really spoke upon but like
if you can tap into past emotions you
know that's always good I got some songs
like that so honestly it's not always
like a cookie cutter for every song yeah
but when it comes to like those deeper
ones it comes to you know either
emotions that are going on bro when I
first met my wife I made two songs for
her right yeah I never made no songs for
no females oh wow
uh the first song I made man
it was because of the first time I met
her and everything and then
the second one like she lives obviously
so I live here this is how she bought
right I bought the other house down the
street now she bought this house after I
did like a couple years
um and been sitting around sorry at a
wedding
and I ended up getting a ride home with
him you know getting her number planting
my seeds you know yeah yeah things like
things like that long story short but
bro I was like on my way home and it was
raining I was on my Ray J [__] like if I
had one type of [__] you know if you're
going through something in the moment so
the way this this is what I always look
at life I try to be as efficient as
possible so if I can put myself in the
position to capture any Vibe or any
emotion at any time yep I'm gonna win
and that is that's what the artist does
bro that's what artist does and that's
what I'm trying to say is like
I got a studio here at this house and at
that house so anytime I could record and
lay down whatever I'm feeling like if my
co-workers give me [__] at that that day
at work you know my co-workers is
[__] me my boss is [__] me I come
home and rap about it yeah you know
someone hit my car I come home right
about it you know or at least take that
energy and put it into some you know or
and in that way it's therapy
um also you know when I feel on like
just some bouncy like whatever
like a lot of times I picture the music
video in my head maybe not even
necessarily the music video but like the
scenario and like yeah or even like
yourself in the music video sometimes
I'll be picture like if I if I was in
the music video the song was done what
would the music video be like I'll let
myself do that and sometimes it'll help
me just totally Vibe the [__] out so
like as if my raps were narrating
yeah whatever yeah or a book you know
whatever it may be
um but that I try to tell a story like
that and I'll be doing that so fluently
and the way I be rhyming sometimes is
crazy
it's Bobby bars and I know I hold myself
to that standard when I say Bobby bars
for me to come out with these crazy ass
bars but I'm not out of this world as
far as thinking like trying to do this
ABC rap and [__] like I am very clever
but most of my [__] comes from real life
true
things
you know I tell I'll put people on a
game like a lot of times I'll say how I
move or how how you should and shouldn't
move you know like like you gotta have
you know faith in yourself you know you
gotta trust in the process see where it
goes and where it takes this type [__]
you know
um Bobby rounding my ass off and coming
up with these crazy schemes that just
it's like oh [__] that was smooth and it
was game
you know I mean I'm not trying to like
Mary had a little lamb these cats or Dr
Seuss some music yeah yeah rhyme just
because it Rhymes it's like you're
trying to communicate something too yeah
and so I guess so the way I'd be rapping
too I'd be articulating to a point to
where it's like you can understand what
I'm saying or you could just read my
lyrics
even and understand what I'm saying
other people would just be rhyming to
rhyming and they just
round without even making a whole
sentence well yeah a lot of people it's
interesting to see
I mean because like like I've been
getting better too so I can see like old
mistakes that I made too but it's
interesting to see the things that
people apparently don't hear it's like
bro like if you hit play on what you
just showed me do you think that sounds
like like don't that sound off to you
like where they're like wrapping off the
rapping off beat or they like don't have
um
because a lot of times you got your
piece of paper in front of you and
you're like all right I wrote exactly so
I'm gonna say it word for word but like
sometimes it ain't enunciated right
sometimes you got to get rid of that
word sometimes you have to like uh make
this word more of a slang sometimes this
one has to be the and sometimes you
gotta say like the you know because you
just gotta work with and that comes with
feeling it as you're writing it you know
it's not like cooking yeah yeah it's
just fluid bro it's music it's fluid
that's that's what it is but you gotta
find your rap language
you feel what I'm saying like I know
what you're saying taking out like the
the eye
or the um had or was like something take
and it's all about syllables so the way
I write is very symmetrical
and to the point to where like my
cadences rhyme yeah okay this is flow in
a puzzle to where it's like even if I'm
not Ryan rhyming it feels like I am
because it's a Melody yeah you see what
I'm saying yeah so it's it's like so um
there's a philosopher Terence McKenna he
talked he talks pretty heavily about
there's there's silence in between words
in that articulation of the silence is
what makes the words what they are so
like uh he he gives this example he's
kind of a dorky guy but he basically
starts talking gibberish but he has he
enunciates and he pauses and and he's
basically saying you kind of understand
the emotions I'm trying to communicate
he's like snorkels
he like does weird [__] like that but
you say in a certain way that it's
communicating something beyond the words
and so yeah like that's the same thing
with hip-hop and I like dude like I said
like would you say rap language you like
learning your rap it's not even just
hip-hop bro it's music in general but
but I think it's your own I think we all
like like when I'm writing hip-hop like
I'm such a fan of hip-hop but like I
would hate for myself to inadvertently
be trying to mimic someone so like I
want to find shakes hip-hop language
like Bobby you want to find Bobby's
hip-hop language right
back but if I subconsciously emulate
somebody in any way shape or form they
ain't got nothing to do with me trying
to be like somebody so inadvertently
that's cool because motherfucker's been
like oh yeah you sound you sound like
Cube you sound like Nipsey you look like
this whatever I give a damn I'm just
trying to do me yeah if I sound like cuz
in for some reason that just happened to
be you know people you know people say
that story they mean it as a compliment
but like I don't know how to feel about
that like oh you sound just like oh so
and so I'm like
thanks but like I wasn't trying to like
I don't know where to put that come but
like yeah it's something
it's dope though man it's real it's
really I mean I'm with you I just
totally resonate with that man it's
really dope to like find your voice you
know like I've I love poetry and that
sort of stuff but like the more and more
of developing my own like rap voice and
articulating what I'm trying to say and
a lot of times bro the dopest thing is
the therapy aspect of it when you like
step back you're writing and you're in
the zone and you step back and you're
like damn bro I just processed some [__]
like I just worked through that I'm like
yeah
honestly honestly I'd be surprised
myself sometimes man
that'd be the [__] but like
man when I first started getting on the
mic
I thought I was just gonna be a
recording artist you know like prior to
2022 I had never performed
on stage ever so all the 2022 I was kind
of just honing that in and I was still
making a lot of music too
um
I got a lot of performances under my
belt and quite a bit of time on the mic
now
and I'm starting to get paid for it it
feels good and I actually really enjoy
it
first few times again with Mike hearing
myself back in the headphones like when
was some real [__] I'm like damn like
being a fan as I'm spitting it you know
I'm like oh you know that [__] sounds so
good like
to the point where it's like oh damn you
know but man this journey has been great
and
I don't foresee to ever quitting man
um
I think this big bet [__] is forever
music this music is forever I've already
laid down a platform that's continuously
growing and giving other people
opportunities
um
and may I just lead by example G to be
real like I'm starting to manage a
couple folks
starting to promote for some people also
um booking some folks like because they
see what I'm doing for myself they come
to me for the service
well I think how you carry yourself says
a lot too man
I feel like that's yeah
probably just because I don't play and
I'm not trying to
I really don't really need to be taking
nobody's money like that you know I'm
doing it for the art and for the growth
and you know I love to build a team of
strong players who want to play with me
you know so we can go to the ship and
um not to say I'm not gonna help
somebody else who might not be strong at
that very moment but I see things in
folks and I also see things in music and
I see things in life that other people
don't necessarily got the vision for
um I wouldn't say is all the way you
know my destiny to
share that Vision with everybody but or
to teach other people that like I
probably might be a teacher or coach
someday but it's more like
it's more like I'm I'm utilizing the
the vision I was given right now and uh
also you know sharing that with the
people who are riding with me and trying
to share that knowledge with the folks
who were in the gym shooting with me
you know um and those who are
like-minded man because bro when you're
when you go from being
a consumer
to a producer of content whether it is
videos or you know poetry or music or
whatever it may be
the
the understanding of it is a whole lot
different
you know like at the beginning bro if
you could tell yourself what you know
now five years ago
you would have had how many steps
forward
you know you would have had a few legs
up because of what you went through and
what you learned and if I could help
expedite any time for anyone else that's
willing to put the work in
like why not because I'm gonna forever
grow and if there's somebody who's you
know 10 steps ahead of me that someday
might put me up on game to get me if it
had more ahead than I am why would I not
accept that you know and I don't feel
like you know
I don't feel like all this is just for
me
and I make music for myself therapy and
because I like how it sounds and because
I feel like I do got a vision for it in
the ear for it
but it's more than just Music Man
it's about ownership you know like
I don't pay no car notes you know
we we landlords over here man
like
hold myself and my wife and we trying to
get another one we taking vacations
doing real grown people's [__] and
trying to
it's not even pursuing happiness we are
earning it
you know and if you know that it takes a
little bit of sacrifice man if I get
anybody some advice when you and your
early 20s run it up work as hard as you
can you feel me and that's not meaning
go to school when you take a path
that you feel is is right and Tunnel
Vision on that because later in life
you're gonna wish you would have kept on
yeah yeah bro I always tell people I
always say like find your greatness you
know like because a lot of times we're
kind of comparing ourselves to who
everybody else is great and it's like
where am I at when I'm 24 like they're
over here and I ain't doing this like
bro whatever you got an interest in
whatever you're passionate about
whatever you know about whatever lights
you up like you get talking about the
subject and it just sends you a blaze
bro and you know about it and and like
it just fuels you up just keep digging
at that bro like if it's music if it's
whatever if you're passing in anything
what's your first responsibility is to
put yourself in the position to do that
yeah
to pursue that so it's like
when we're kids they say oh you know
that the job fairs you want to be a
fireman policeman doctor you know what
do you want to be when you grow up Bobby
[__] I don't know
and whether I know then or not
think about what's going to stop you
from pursuing your dreams once you do
figure out what you love
right
what's going to stop you money rent
baby mamas whatever
right
so put yourself in the position to
follow your dreams or if you don't know
what you're doing right now if you don't
know what you're gonna do with the rest
of your life if you don't have a passion
yet that you know if you haven't found
your calling
put yourself in the position to answer
that call when it comes
you know what I mean you think I woke up
and said oh I want to go work for a
paper mill
now I was over there for over six years
man I've been I still work in the
industry in the work field man you you
worked at warehouser too huh yes sir
five years man we didn't wake up and say
we want dude that's all about doing what
you're supposed to do
right and I'm not doing it because Uncle
Sam's telling me I'm doing it because I
want to follow my dreams ain't nobody
gonna give it to me
how am I supposed to have all this
studio equipment all these resources to
do music if I didn't put myself in the
position too no one else would have done
it for me yeah nor would I have had any
Outlet so where would I be right now if
I wasn't doing music I don't know but I
wouldn't be here and where I am today is
where I'm supposed to be
well I think it's huge bro that you I
think what what happens with a lot of
people is that nine to five that that
Mill job beats us up and then we get off
and we just want to like shut it off we
just want to smoke smoke the thoughts
away we want to drink the thoughts away
we want to just video game out whatever
it is and like you know live your life
and enjoy your life however you want to
enjoy it but you got to be honest with
yourself like you put in your work at
the paper mill but when you're off you
know put in the time on yourself on your
future like like make put some goals on
the calendar I feel like but dude I
really love that you said that I feel
like that's actually like super huge I
was super excited when you were saying
that like set yourself up to answer the
call you know because sometimes we're
like man what's my problem that one was
smooth yeah that was good bro that was
beautiful I'd love for that please top
that one for me oh 100 that's a clip
right there clip it clip it I got to
tell myself it's smooth enough I hope I
said it's moving no no it was beautiful
because I really do believe in that and
and you know what even me bro when I was
younger like I couldn't even see I
didn't even give myself like I was hard
on myself and I there was there was ways
where I could have been a little bit
more delicate with myself in in a way
and and I just say that because like I'd
be working Monday through Thursday I'd
do four tens graveyard and then the
weekends I'd be they're working clubs or
I'd be driving to Portland to go to
audio engineering school and like in my
head during those times I'm dreading the
whole every night I'm at work I'm
dreading it I'm being like negative to
myself like man I just want to be doing
this I ain't doing this but what I the
thing about it is like I was doing it
I'm working on it right now yeah like
bro like literally like I'm doing the
thing right now I'm putting the time and
like yeah maybe I'm [__] you know
it's it's three o'clock in the morning
and I'm stapling some industrial staper
to sides of lumber you know but in six
hours I'm driving to Portland and I'm
learning about mixing and mastering and
like this kind of [__] you know so yeah
bro I I love that like put yourself in
the position and then also yeah just be
easy on yourself if you are doing it bro
like put your time in get your money pay
your bills keep your girl right keep
your family right keep your kids right
you know get your dog fed keep your
lights on and then the rest of the time
work on that goal work on that future
you know yeah in in the more you
solidify everything else
the more
you're able to
delegate time to other things and you
know putting yourself in the position
it's all about
you know when that
opportunity and preparation meet bro
it's
man there's so many people who have
opportunities they wasn't prepared for
and I think
all I want to do is make sure I am
prepared for what will come
and
the fact that you know I control
what I do to make that happen or to move
forward like I think that
man I'm set up for success and
um
it's a slow grind bro look I'm not
on the XXL
fight for this year you know what I mean
it's not crazy like that
but
I'm I'm out here not doing money
necessarily I've been doing music for uh
money and and revenue like that it's
man it's a passion that I put myself in
the position
to pursue his
um something I feel like I should have
already been doing but the capacity and
the quality
that I'm able to do music in and produce
music at is
not where it would have been if I would
have started before I was prepared
you know like prior to being
situated it's like sit back
let me get situated
sit back and watch a real [__]
demonstrated
and you know now I'm just demonstrating
what
I prepared myself for
yeah I mean like living life honestly if
I wouldn't live the life that I did not
say I wouldn't have content but
you wouldn't have the content you have
today and you might not be hearing me
speak might not be listening to my music
but I think ahead and bro I'm trying to
leave a legacy
I set myself up to where a lot these
songs are forever man
and they may not all pop right now I got
some bangers you know but I think the
the dope is [__] is that my whole
catalog from beginning to end is out on
all platforms
other than the ones I scrapped and was
not out yet because the vault is pretty
heavy right now but
I got 20 songs out you know in in the
last you know three and a half years
I stayed consistent
you know and you can see the growth you
can see the growth what's crazy is I'm
getting more and more fans and listeners
today
but like my third most streamed song is
my first song ever put out
people keep going back to see where it
started from yeah yeah you know I mean
whether man to tell people whether it's
good or bad because you see people oh
I'm just a SoundCloud rapper oh I'm just
doing this doing that man that big on
yourself man because ain't nobody else
gonna bet big on you until you prove
that you work betting on because if you
ain't gonna bet on yourself who else
gonna bet on you and when I say bad you
know somewhat a calculator risk if you
know don't spend too much money but bet
on yourself with time effort
and thought you know like
think some [__] though
you know it's not just gambling we just
throw money and throw resources that
it's about
calculating what you're doing
and then betting big on
to the point to where it's like
you can't you can't do you can't deny it
you can't deny it it's there brother
work the work shows up for itself it's
like when you go to hit submit when you
go to hit post on that song like at last
like how many hundreds of hours really
went into that song of like editing it
writing it getting it right the ad-libs
producing it everything you know you
finally hit post the reason why you're
going to believe in it is because you
put the time into it you know like it
speaks for itself like that bro I got
songs coming on this next album
two of them were recorded like two years
ago
yeah I mean it's just like about what
makes sense and when the time is like
you know sometimes it's tweaking this
doing that or finishing this hook or
this little piece there you know or what
project does it go on or is it a single
yeah like
I got one that's all in-house produced
it's gonna be five songs and they were
all executively produced by me and
co-produced by me but all the Beats were
mainly produced by JC Banker which is my
in-house producer he's my homie my
business party
the dude on the podcast with me oh yeah
yeah that's what's up
yeah man I mean it's dope to get better
it's dope to improve so what's your I
mean like obviously like Rapids your
thing I mean that's what you want to
represent but are you just gonna keep
getting better at producing making beats
like he's just gonna keep doing all of
it just
getting better yeah well my passion is
actually producing a lot yeah uh music
in the hole like I want to executively
produce too so I'll be sending out
reference tracks all that yeah because I
am a lot I wish I could sing sing
I can sing a little bit I got a little
uh I call it Hood hymns
you know like
oh yeah yeah it's like awesome hood [__]
a little bit
um Melodies like that I don't be doing
no like ballad type [__] but
um my buddy Willie Beaman he got these
crazy riffs he got a voice like a flute
you know yeah and a few of the people
who be singing some Hooks and stuff for
me
um but the thing is if you can
communicate if you got the idea as like
the writer and you communicate bro all
right then do this with your voice then
that's that's what's up like you don't
always have to do it if you can
communicate it that's part of the gift
too and and I do communicate it
um sometimes I just
recorded myself anyways just to not lose
that Vibe or what I was feeling at the
time you know and then I'd be like
sometimes I will or will not use it as
the reference track to send to the
artist that's gonna sing it but like
when I got a certain Cadence or a Melody
it's like all right then do your own
thing do the rest on it but like this is
what we're doing and I'll send the
lyrics and everything like I've done
that a few times now two of those are
actually going to be on the next project
I'd be ghost writing too
for a lot of people out here yeah I'd be
ghost riding I sell songs sell verses I
sell features so when like I'd be
selling hooks like just written hooks
without me doing them I'll say I'll sell
hooks with me on them
um [__] I'll just write things for
people I take I bring in split sheets
and
get Rider shares see this is what like
people who ain't in the music they might
not know that like this is what you do
like like the like in in the hip-hop
industry there's like a lot of the
people that you listen to that you love
like they write for each other like a
lot of the a lot of being like popular
pop stuff that we know of our favorite
hip-hop artists actually wrote you know
like Pharrell's behind a lot of dope ass
[__] that we don't know Pharrell's new
names you know like it's dope there's a
lot of I think you I think people hear
ghost riding and they're like like
what's it like you're Faking It Whatever
but it's actually like no it's a little
different it's this whole like you just
call it co-writing like call it
co-writing because like you know I I've
never actually written like a whole ass
song word for word for somebody but
think about it like if they know who
they are as an artist and there's not
some label really contract controlling
what they're saying in their exact image
like you can write them a song and then
they'll take in take an ad to it you
know for the most part
but when it comes to like say like a B I
produce or something there's a certain
Cadence that goes with it you know for a
hook mainly like yeah that'll just be
written but most people will let they
probably get in the way like all around
whoa think about it like people don't
learn
that it does
there's so many hands and so many songs
that people don't realize until they get
signed you know what I mean in that
whole time that they had mediocre music
was because they had this product Oh I
just it's all me but it's like if you
took a little bit of constructive
criticism on a change a couple words it
could have made the difference yeah yeah
you understand that one little pocket
that you [__] up on the beat drop
could have been different you never know
like and you could have found that new
pocket by just someone who was chilling
in like someone's little brother who was
chilling in the studio that day is like
yo like it kind of sounds weird like
that what if you did this and he just
suggests that and then suddenly like you
see him you know in in two years you see
him on the song credits because he just
said like yo what if you did this you
know that's that's kind of how it works
man you're trying to like as an artist
you're trying to just create the
environment to where the Muse could flow
through the conduit you know and the
artist is the conduit and sometimes like
people in that room are the conduit too
you're just trying to create a Vibe so
y'all can like put out the Nets you know
and like catch some [__] in the Nets
bags
yeah yeah
it's like I call it producing Vibes you
know like
JC that's all he does JC banko he's my
business partner that's all he does is
make beats really he's a dope ass artist
and probably one of the best artists out
here himself but he he is just producing
his his thing and um
man we'll be in there and he just
produces Vibes you know like
made it he made a couple beats the last
couple he made for me were specific for
collab sessions I had
right uh you know my little brother
right
chilling oh yeah yeah okay okay yeah so
he actually rap too he raped too low
low-key not like professionally had no
rap name type [__] but he called as hell
and his pins actually
pretty perverse he uh JC made us a whole
B pack just for the weekend my little
brother was gonna come down you know we
made three four songs uh he made a bunch
of Beats specifically for uh these other
two artists that are pretty big in
Portland that I did music with just
recently and it's about producing Vibes
man and
um
however it is that you're best at doing
that is the best environment to create
and I think that
it's always what's best for the song you
know what I mean in my eyes like shoot
I come from the air where there's a
bunch of verses on everything and you
know I'll be throwing I'll be putting
three verses on every song Sometimes
five verses like you know to the point
where I started making shorter songs
Just because I know attention spans and
all that but but man this is whatever is
best for the song to be honest and
sometimes the Vibes be so crazy you just
can't quit it's just you know
yeah you keep this one gotta get rid of
that isn't that the craziest thing man
like there used to be I mean we back in
the day we listened to five minute songs
bro you couldn't even beg someone to
listen to a five minute song now you can
you couldn't pay them bro like all the
features are dope like now they now
they'll just like re-upload they'll get
rid of this feature and then release the
same song with this feature and it's
it's weird that's just them trying to
play like this the charts and [__] but
yeah I mean that's what it is though is
like you wanna it's it's the same thing
part of being in a music environment in
a place where there's people creating is
like you'll learn quick that if you have
an ego you're not going to be really
super welcome I mean there's like a
level of
using your ego to find the r and not
letting your ego likes get in any sort
of way of the arcs like if it's if it's
blocking the view for like the real art
to get through it's it's very apparent
like everybody in the room could feel
that you know have you ever gone through
a phase where you were engineer folks
like recording
yeah nothing it's like a super
professional setting but casually
so I wouldn't say RC was super
professional but
um I still I still engineer sessions to
this day and man the the
man the different types of artists you
get you know there's some people who
honestly just pay to be able to dictate
everything
or people who pay just to do what they
want to do
and other times the artists are more
receptive to constructive criticism and
doing what's best for the song but
that's when you got artists who just
think they're the [__] and have no room
for improvement like they're already at
the top
you know and then there's artists who
want real feedback from people who
listen to a [__] ton of music and also
make music themselves you know
um
so it's different sometimes it's crazy
sometimes it's comedy sometimes it's
annoying but so I mean sometimes you're
just getting paid too like it's all
right to like if someone just has their
preference and they're like yo to be
real I don't really need like your
perspective on it I'm just trying to
record my [__] it's just kind of boring
though but hey you're just getting paid
yeah you just wrote It's like bro you
could have done this by yourself like I
don't have to be in the room for real
but I take your money yeah yeah it's
almost like because we try to get more
of an experience like that
um it's not like that too much anymore
pretty much exclusive like we produce a
lot of the people that we record yeah
so it's like
we already got our hands in the track
you know
um yeah I like doing it all at once too
I feel like that's when you could really
like get the most creativity out of it
like I think it's really cool when like
say I produce something or JC produces
them we get an artist that comes in on
it you know being able to like have them
have the producer there while you're
recording
ad take away or mess with the beat like
why you're because some people like oh
like this be so hard I just wish that
this was lower this was higher or you
know like I just bro two weeks ago I
made a Beat
and I was kind of just messing around
but then I ended up finding like
some type of sequence that's just I'm
like oh and I started rapping to it you
know what I'm saying this is why I need
to start doing making beats that I just
make that face to and I did it and I
showed uh two people
and dude was like man
I just wish it sounded a little more
like or whatever you know like but they
was loving it
so the one the other dude loved the
first version he bought the first
version from me the second one I came
back instead of like a you know blue
blue blue blue
Mallet type sound I did an electric
guitar like
yeah and
he bought the second version that was it
yeah so like I saw two versions of the
same beat and I made I had to make sure
that they were different for sure more
than just the melody right
um but like the two different people
in the same week gonna be that didn't
even finish it
yeah
you know what I mean in to
just like get in and produce like that
it's a different feeling but like not
only did the one dude by the beat but he
got me on the track too
and I probably spit the hardest verse on
me that's nice that's probably you made
me sell track and then it was a
different feeling that was the first
time doing that actually I like that uh
he made me stretch it to four verses
and um then the other dude didn't show
up so we squashed it to three but they
gave me the third verse yeah
they shouldn't have gave me worse but
they did
that's what's up they did man
this is hard
where are you getting your Beats
uh bro I've honestly I've been YouTube
surfing a lot lately I'll I'll do uh
I'll start with type beats I know it's
an eye roller but I'll start with type
beats just like get me going but uh a
lot of times I like once I find a dope
beat like I have a couple people that I
follow that I just like a lot of their
beats I'll just hit play on it and like
pretty much the first or second time I
listen to it I'll know if I have if I
can write a song to it all what I do is
all so like I literally put headphones
in I'll go on YouTube
hit play if I think all right I gotta
I'll get a piece of paper I'll grab out
my notes on my phone and then I'll just
spend like the next probably two three
hours right until the end of it and then
it's like at the end I'm like all right
did I actually say something and then
I'll decide if I feel like recording it
or whatever but yeah YouTube is where
I'm a lot honestly and then uh like when
it comes to like so I'm not really the
best I'm not the best beat maker I'm not
the best producer I have fun with it I
dink around a lot I'm just not super
disciplined with it I'm I'm oh I mess
around with my own stuff but I just I
never try to like
I've only made a few things for other
people but uh I I use loops and samples
a lot like I have a arcade output if you
heard of that it's like nothing wrong
with that yeah yeah but I mean I'm a DJ
it's literally how I work I've been
using loops and samples for for 11 years
you know so yeah it ain't really that
abnormal for me anyway but it's just it
helps me get ideas out like I'll just
I'll lay a loop I'll record it I'll
wander around here and just start
writing poetry to it writing words to it
whatever you know this is clean yeah
this is clean I mean I I'm not super
citizen to producer [__] yet
um I do want to dig more until it start
making more beats but like I said I made
a couple official ones that I've
actually sold a few that I actually made
songs on
um
and you know those beats I I get Mason
mastered just because
there's people who got way more skills
in my team than I do that's so good at
that some people are really so I know
some people who are just like just so
good wizards bro Wizards see and I could
put my pride in the side in the way and
be like oh I did all myself and I'll
have to be amazing and not sound the
best it could sound or I could say hey
I'm gonna have my bro you know proofread
it from me or touch it up you know and
um yeah I ain't got no problem with that
with that being said bro I think it
would be dope to get on track with you
man absolutely I would love it man I
would love it you got any uh well let me
uh after this I'll send you like like
something I've been you could hear my
style a little bit and then if you got
anything uh any any beats floating
around or it gives you an ideas or
whatever
um yeah I think uh regardless of style
bro I've been reaching in my bag so like
I still do me on every track but like
I've been reaching in that bag
um man just a year ago actually so we
shot the music video last New Year's
um I did this song
it's called bad Munda but I call it the
translate song okay so I'm doing this
series where I'm translating the songs
that are other languages but I got my
one English verse translating the whole
[__]
and this song is all in Hindi
so uh so he's a Hindu cat and I have you
can't you don't know what he's saying
because it's different language the
whole time into my verse right and then
I break down the whole track
damn that's awesome bro I love that and
that's actually dope for this time too
yeah we're mixing a lot of different
languages right now not to say that you
and I speak different languages what I'm
trying to say is that oh I'm not I'm not
opposed to any style any genre like if I
feel it
I feel it
if I'm not with it then I'll just be
like let's go move on to the next we'll
find one though you know yeah absolutely
like type [__] but if there's some like
grunt [__] even like bro I get down or
whatever it's just if I feel it I feel
it yeah and I'll get it and I'll do my
rap [__] honestly like I'm crazy with
the hooks but
my name is Bobby bars and that's what
I'm coming with okay dude well I
definitely want to make some stuff man I
just I'm I'm pretty I'm Not confined my
genres never happen I just whatever
sounds cool like I'm I'll sing rap I
don't care how my voice sounds we'll put
a bunch of effects on it we'll put no
effects on it like if it sounds dope in
the song that's all I care about same as
you bro so I feel like I feel like we
probably actually make some cool [__]
always I wish I was up in that area bro
I'd actually just like rolled rolled
down to Vancouver and come kick it for a
day but that'd be dope I was hoping to
be in the studio today so I could give
you a little sneak peek but bro I got I
got the blue and black foam everywhere I
got the pictures of all the old school
rappers you know all everything it's
just
super inviting creative space
environment and Vibe is is part of bro
like literally exactly you're saying
like creating that space is what it's
What DJ Khaled does is what Rick Rubin
does it's these people in creating an
environment with lights with smell with
your energy like you just being calm and
like here that brings everybody that
invites everybody else to be there and
then the best piece of art can flow out
of everybody just by environment man
yeah no doubt no doubt no doubt you know
um bro I think we make some good music
together if not I think definitely we
can have some conversations that we made
just inadvertently Inspire each other to
make some dope songs anyways
whether it's individually or not bro
cause
with this music [__] man when when I'm
going through things I'll be coming up
with these Concepts that just
they're simple I just think it's hard
for people to articulate those type of
feelings or I guess those type of
visuals
I guess it would be audios but those
type of words like
to put to that emotion or to that
feeling or you know like oh damn [__] I
would have said the same thing but you
didn't because you know type of thing
it's like but I did because oh [__] you
got the vision to see visually yeah well
but that thing is like the artist with
their words is painting like the vision
for you and that's what like even though
it says consumers before we ever wrote
anything that's what we loved we love
when like oh bro I like they know
exactly I I felt that exact same thing I
just know how to put words for it and
then someone like just saying he exactly
lived it and you're like what like I
feel heard I've never even met anybody
who went through these things like me
and then you hear it hear someone say in
their art man and that's what that's
beautiful or even or even get inspired
or whatever you know I feel like with a
lot of the
I guess I'll I call it wisdom but like
with a lot of the ways that I'm able to
perceive life
for what it really is
then like emulating that on on a track
into a story you know what I mean and
then absolutely like recapping something
for real or
um the hardest thing is just emotions
you know like sometimes for people to
just relay on the track like you can go
and read like
reiterate on some type of story that how
actually happened is one thing but on an
emotion that you had about something is
even deeper and you know I I'll be
tapping into [__] like that yeah yeah
word like revisiting it with some wisdom
with some perspective
yeah for real because I mean bro
you you're only
like what we know they they always tell
us what they say like education is key
true but
it's about what you're educated in
and
you know you got to be educated on
yourself before you can even really go
learn anything else real life lessons
you know like
I advise anybody to go learn from
someone else's mistakes and I know that
sounds cliche but with that being said
you're less likely to make those same
ones
but inevitably you're gonna make your
own so make sure you live you live and
you learn
in order to live again because if you
don't learn then
this
that's a road that
you need to get off
you know because like what I said at the
beginning I said
um any time invested that you didn't
learn is it or any time you spent that
you didn't learn is a bad investment
um
people spending time on something you
don't learn nothing like
you and you wasting time
yeah right bro I think we're getting our
own way of learning a lot of the times
too it's like we'll be stubborn about it
man we'll be like we'll be we'll be
blaming other people and we'll be
blocking the learning because we're
blaming other people or we'll be like
I'm I'm here because this thing happened
to me and I can't ever like you know get
myself out of it and then suddenly we've
blocked the opportunity to learn about
ourselves to grow just realize it's an
option now though
like instead of waiting five years down
the road to learn from what you did
like try to learn from it real time
you know like realize that the time to
learn is now so like if there's you know
even prior to making a mistake just
learning that you're capable of taking
the wrong road
and put the measures in place to not
go down that path you know what I mean
it's I mean it sounds simple coming out
my mouth but I know it's a struggle and
people have
different obstacles than I have and all
people have different obstacles but
you know
um it's all about putting yourself in
the position to get over those as long
as this obstacle gives you bigger packs
and bigger legs to jump over the next
one whatever it may be you know like
then it was worth it yeah but if it did
nothing but break you down then it
wasn't worth it right and you didn't
make the best of it so I guess I just
try to make the best of every situation
good bad or ugly because if it's good
then we blessed if you know if it's bad
then I learned from it and I'm still
alive and I'm blessed yeah well but you
almost got to because then you don't
feel like you're in control you feel
like the world's just kind of kicking
your ass in a way like if you aren't
like all right what can I learn from it
and that's not like I'm not trying to
disregard what anybody's going through
too I'm not trying to like but you know
like I've been through some bad stuff
but that don't mean that I'm trying to
compare my bad stuff to yours like the
worst thing you've been through is the
worst thing you've been through and
that's that's all right that's that's
life but like yeah and disclaimer and me
me saying all this is about me talking
to my previous self like hey man you
should have known better but now you do
so let's get it in and do what you know
you're supposed to be doing now yeah
yeah you know go ahead yeah but well
that's just what I try man I try to I
always say that with this podcast is
like I always try to think like if I
could talked to my like 16 year old self
just that little knucklehead if he would
have listened if he didn't would have
heard anything like how could I say it
you know like what what could I teach
him how could I word it and be truthful
and just be like yo you don't have to
make this mistake that I made that's
what I always try to keep the
perspective of as The Listener so that's
perfect
right but I mean
everybody does have to make mistakes
I mean learn from other people's
mistakes is one thing but naturally you
know but once you start making some
mistakes like man just just just learn
from it and and get to the point to
where you can recognize that mistake
before it happens and you can rise above
it you know no matter what it is whether
you're you know 10 years older
50 years old you know it's
people have choices every single day to
do the right thing or the wrong thing
and you know people who have learned and
know better
it's all about knowing better but you
gotta realize some [__] first you know
so take off the blinders pull the
earplugs out
and just realize what time it is and
yeah stop sitting back and letting life
take you down river and start
revving up that engine and follow your
dreams and put yourself in the position
to get up that mountain you know
um
we are going to be test tested
and we are all gonna have a time where
we're gonna have opportunities that we
wish we were prepared for
and I think deep down if you have a
passion or a love for something
and your end goal is to have an
opportunity in that
just get yourself prepared to capitalize
on that opportunity and don't wait on
nobody else to move and don't let nobody
else stop you from doing that because
the absolute faith is the faith that
something's gonna happen regardless
you know it's it's not about if it's
about when mm-hmm
yeah yeah it's not like is this a lesson
it's like this is a lesson what what can
I learn from it you know because we feel
unmoved we feel bro I feel like a lot of
young men you're absolutely dropping
Bars by the way uh of course double r z
but uh yeah bro I really I feel like
it's important for you to share too
because
I don't know it seems like it seems like
there's like like young men could really
use he just hearing that you know like a
lot like we get caught up as men we deal
with [__] on our own a lot bro we like
we suck it down we deal with it we you
know slam it inside and we walk around
with a lot of guilt and shame and like
man I wish I would have done this it's
like well you didn't bro but like what
can you do today you know like you move
forward like you just let let go of that
you know if you have an old version of
yourself that's like LED you to where
you are right now
and and you don't want to be that
anymore that's all right bro like just
as much as you should recognize
when you not moving forward you need to
recognize when you are
just like you said earlier like going to
school and doing all that you're like oh
you know you gotta recognize when you
are moving forward
be proud of every step G every single
step forward because at the end of the
day say tomorrow is my last day you
couldn't say I wasn't working towards
them
my compliment accomplishments is my
consistency
I'm consistent I've already accomplished
more than what I ever thought I could
right at the beginning
so you just gotta know when
when you are moving forward and be proud
of yourself and then trust in the
process
and man see how far it takes you trust
in the process the pro and honestly the
ups and downs of every process if you
actually endure it how it needs to be
endured man
it gonna shape you into exactly who you
need to be
and it honestly is going to teach you
more about yourself than you ever knew
and and it's a it's
you know if you if something so deep
down and you tells you to take that
Journey that has a process that you need
to endure like that
that's what you're supposed to be doing
in the tunnel vision on that get it done
you know
and and be proud of yourself every time
you take a step forward
and every time you
take a step back [__] learn from it yeah
and make sure that makes you strong
enough for that next step to be worth
two steps you know what I mean that's
why I said like [__] if you didn't jump
over that hurdle well however many times
you tried to I hope you gain enough
muscles in your legs to jump over it two
three times over the next time that's
the point that's the point you might
roll down the hill but you got to keep
walking on up until you get to the other
side see yep yeah it won every time you
fail that's it that's a you're building
some leg muscle like you didn't fail we
were talking about he didn't fail like
you you're getting a little stronger so
tomorrow you're going to be able to go
you're like a half inch higher you know
you're building up muscle
real that's how it is real you know and
that that motivation I I keep that fire
bro I keep that fire I'll let none none
hold me back
um
man it's just all all Ford with the
music thing uh and it's more than just
music I hate calling it that because bro
it's a brand now you know yeah
you know it's a brand I see people
around town randomly wearing my shirts
and my hoodies you know and uh
like I've been out in Vancouver for
[__] like 12 years now
something like that 10 no like 10 years
hmm
10 years and um Vancouver Portland area
kind of been living in the same area but
yeah man like
I don't really get out and I'm not like
that sociable all the time but like the
people I meet every time
they leave a conversation with me they
it usually ends they end up with some
positive game you know and next time I
see them
normally they better you know or
something good happened like
I just preached positivity man I that
there ain't too many people I meet
nowadays that don't respect what I'm
doing
you know
there might be some people who are
envious and you know
who might think that they better
whatever but ain't nobody better at
doing me than me
you know I try to do nothing like nobody
else G
how am I supposed to be better than you
at doing you
okay bro I'm not in competition with you
what are you talking about yeah what the
[__] like that's what I was recording
constructive competition like we are
trying to like better ourselves that's
one thing but it's like I must always be
me I'm gonna be the best me I can be you
know and hopefully the best you can beat
me but at the end of the day I'm only
gonna do what I'm gonna do
and to the best of my capabilities I'm
gonna do that very thing the one that
feeds up in the in into other areas of
your life you know if you're working on
yourself at all times every interaction
like you just said you just run into
someone boom like you maybe you just
just by your demeanor by you being real
by you just communicating and being here
with this person like maybe you just
planted that Bonsai seed you know maybe
maybe they like didn't really hear what
they needed to see to hear at that
moment but in a couple months they're
gonna be like damn you know Bobby said
some [__] like uh that happens a lot
that happens a lot it's profound amen
yeah that happens a lot they'd be like
hey man
you know I didn't really get it when you
first said it but then
man he was right
and then like when this happened like I
just thought about what you said man
you know on some [__] like that and I'm
like
I'm not lying
I'm only trying to keep it real with you
man yeah I wasn't even trying to like
give you any profound knowledge I was
just just being straight up with you and
like that's for real that's where truth
gets in you know yeah for real I ain't
gonna lie to you I'm gonna tell you the
truth sometimes whether it hurts or not
but yeah
um but with that being said man I just
want the better for everybody
um
you know I pre I preach kindness I
preach you know
everybody being grateful to others
um I really do try to promote this
community
creative house type thing you know to
where
we all help each other man I got folks
scouting for uh these festivals and
stuff now
and it's all these people who have that
same mindset trying to bring all the
community and locals and people really
grinding that have the same kind of like
Minds whether like these well I want to
see everybody win and I ain't gonna lie
I'm not trying to surround myself with a
bunch of Scrubs like my friends are my
friends right
and my peoples are my peoples I got a
small circle but with that being said
I'm trying to surround myself around
people who have aspirations
to be great
because I want to be great you know what
I mean and I don't want to be great
for other people to know that I am or to
see that I am
I want to be great because I know that
it's in me to be great
yeah I mean and I know that that is who
I am
so that's meaningless
I think we all got that and I think when
people see it when they see you acting
through it and living through it like it
Sparks something and that they don't
even like they might not even ever felt
before you know what I mean like that
this I'm just set like not not to put
like artists up on this pedestal like
man we're so real and like we just we
like make other people realize the real
self like ain't really trying to picture
you know paint that but there really is
something about you being at pizza
that's like like
we just work on yourself you don't have
you don't even understand the
implications that it has like the domino
effect
like when you're just you're so when
you're just
doing your best in every moment you know
to some extent in every moment that you
can
it's just growing and it's like sparking
it's like little you're bumping into
people and lighting people up man
it's for real it is and there's there's
already folks who like man I wish I
would have listened to you know five
years back when you told me this that
and the other you know and seeing that
I'm still being real doing my thing and
just pushing forward it's like brah
I was keeping it real with y'all wasn't
trying to get nothing at you you know
I'm just trying to keep it real you know
I think at a certain time of my life I
wasn't even in the position to hear
nothing like that neither you know
um
but I think that's why when I did come
into the
entertainment game was the best time for
me because I already knew who I was I
was established as a man I had a career
established as a person
uh knew who I was was able to just keep
it real on the track and I'm not on
there doing music out of desperation not
doing music because I need some money
not doing it because people just told me
to do it because I signed some funky ass
deal it's because it was in me and uh
it's what I'm supposed to be doing right
yeah I mean that's this is a choice
well it speaks man it just speaks for
itself I feel
you know I I feel like everything you're
doing music I feel like it's beautiful
you're building up a community you know
I feel like uh I mean I want to make
sure anybody we're getting up here in
time anybody listening like I mean you
already mentioned
um a few things but like make sure if
anybody's like yo I want to like link up
with Bobby I want to check out his music
I want to go to his next Open Mic like
yo I'm a wrap around like if there's a
spot for me let's get me on this whole
bike like anybody listening wanting to
like check you out more make sure they
know where to find you what you got
coming up your neck what do you say
February 4th your next song Drop lay it
all out yeah so my next song is called
Hold It Down
um it's a solo track
it drops on February 4th on all
platforms
um
stole this song but it's more on some um
you know like racial inequality type
things and um perfect time for the job
Black History Month it'll be a dope
track a lot of feelings in it actually
it's not really no mainstream [__] but
um I got a lot of music following
um yeah it's Bobby bars two r's one Z on
all platforms
so all the socials is b-o-b-y underscore
b-a-r-r-z
um
Spotify Apple music all that it's just
Bobby bars b-a-r-r-z
um every Thursday night I do an open mic
um I actually host it at Darnell's bar
on Main Street
across the street from Main Event in
Vancouver Washington uh
this will be our second one this coming
Thursday this is pretty dope turnout
it's cool man I'll be running these
jokes and all that so I can start I
started writing jokes testing them I
used a couple actually that I tested out
last week I used a couple on my set on
Saturday yeah it's cool man get like bro
it's just gonna make your writing better
you can make you more comfortable on the
mic bro it's just it's it's elevating I
love that you're doing that that's
awesome that's the main thing because it
I mean if you remember me before man
I've always been kind of reserved and
I'm not shy but I'm also not like I'm
not a loud person you know and um being
on the mic and stuff you know I gotta
gotta learn how to
make it entertaining get that time on
the mic to feel comfortable to be myself
because like you know I just was always
in the motive really not talking until I
knew somebody you know but talking to
complete strangers on the mic and
holding a conversation with the same
type of
energy I would hold with somebody I know
it's different it's a different this
skill to hone in and I'm doing that and
you know I'm starting I want to get some
residencies start hosting [__] you know
and um just also give other people
opportunities and already bro me taking
these steps forward have you know it's
it's inspired other people to do a lot
of the same type of stuff and I see it's
booming out here actually in the
entertainment stuff yeah excellent I
love it I love that
yeah hell yeah dude okay so so is that
is it open mic for is it just hip-hop or
is it like poetry or like what is
guitars
Open Mic it's everyone's welcome all
genres of music poetry comedy
um so I do even if you're just a fan of
some entertainment so I call it the day
shift it's it's on Thursday and it's
from five to eight that's for people who
you know work during the day because man
most of them open much was at nine ten
o'clock at night man and I gotta work
too bro so I'm just like I talked to the
owner and I just like hey man modified
like
took me like a month to get him to you
know agree to it we finally got it going
and
[__] man they give me 10 of the bar
great while I'm there you know make a
couple dollars but like I'm really there
just to give
people a chance to put some work in
because a lot of people have to miss out
because they got priorities you know
they gotta go to work yeah uh just like
myself so
I kind of made it to fit my schedule but
other people got somewhere the same
schedule you know well that's exactly
what you want to do I mean you're going
to make Dope music because you think
it's dope and then other people are
gonna think it's dope too you know you
got to work with what you're working
with and it's going to help other people
out and I love that you're creating that
environment in that community and bro
like for real it's just like every
single Thursday you're going to get a
little bit better at your crafting your
bit more comfortable holding the mic
talking in the mic bouncing your like
chill real authentic self versus kind of
like your elevated stage self like me I
always had to like learn all right like
I'm a DJ I gotta be hype up but like
don't play too hard in the character
while like you're just trying to talk on
the mic you don't even be yelling like
if there's a balance that you just like
you know I still struggle with sometimes
but you learn you know it's it's all
it's all stacking up man I think I think
what you're doing is amazing and I think
uh man I hope people definitely go check
it out Vancouver I think it's awesome
appreciate it appreciate it yeah the old
Mike's cool man I got some more shows
coming up I'll have all those days
posted
um like I said Bobby bars two hours one
Z on everything yeah um on YouTube it's
big bad Studios b-i-g b-e-t Studios
um
that's the logo right there yes sir Ace
Boogie oh I'll put that in the
description too so they can click on it
all as well
okay yeah bet bet yeah also have uh shop
Bobby bars online store if you guys want
to get some hats
shirts coffee mugs phone cases whatever
you want
um
yeah bro it's a pleasure absolutely man
it was dope to link up I'm glad that you
uh I'm glad that you reached out man
thank you for doing that and uh man keep
inspiring keep doing what you're doing I
want to link up yeah like hit me up
let's uh let's chat like later on this
week or whatever about making some music
together I would love to create with you
bro
hell yeah that'd be dope too bro I think
bro and because it's been so long I
think there's a lot to catch up on we
could probably do part two of this
um I'm down again on another episode one
of these times let's talk about some new
stuff we probably format it and actually
come up with some subjects to touch on
um but no this was cool smooth I
appreciate it man what time is it over
there
uh 9 20. oh damn all right yeah no it
ain't too bad I've got a my schedule's
been super weird sometimes like I start
work at midnight like my job is to like
take down the shows sometimes so my
sleep schedule is all weird lately you
never know but it's all right
that's crazy all right bro well I
appreciate you again listeners take care
of yourself check out Bobby I got all
the links in the description check that
out and then if you're around on
Thursday in Vancouver man drop by the
open mic night drop by the day shift and
uh Bobby what we'll be in touch thank
you again bro it was really great to
catch up with you and and just from a
friend perspective and someone who grew
up in the same town I'm just I'm
inspired by you I love what you're doing
like it's just really dope to see like a
you know a fellow homie from when we
were younger just excelling and living
his life and being like just clear-eyed
you know like it seems like you really
got your feet on the ground and I love
that man I wish you well likewise
likewise bro appreciate it yeah yeah all
right bless up man take care of yourself
y'all
conversations
with ourselves
[Music]
knowledge is power
reality is
[Music]